



David Eddings Zingwe Banda

Date of birth: 26 Jan 1993 | **Nationality:** Malawian | **Gender:** Male | **Phone number:**

(+265) 994493393 (Mobile) | Email address: davideddingsz@gmail.com | Twitter:

https://twitter.com/BandaZingwe?t=usXVMUAdHWpX6Si8jXj4XA&s=09

Address: Chirunga street, P.O Box 280, Zomba, 305205, Z, Malawi (Work)

ABOUT ME

I am a trained economist with a master's degree in development economics, specializing in quantitative research. I am passionate about using research as a tool for evidence-based policymaking, with a particular interest in the intersection of food and nutrition security and climate change. I have collaborated with various international organizations, contributing to policy development in the process. Currently, I am lecturing at the University of Malawi.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2 SEP 2023 - CURRENT Zomba, Malawi

ECONOMICS LECTURER UNIVERSITY OF MALAWI

- Teaching Labour Economics, Financial Economics, and Monitoring & Evaluation
- Supervising undergraduate students
- Conducting research work

7 JUL 2023 - 21 JUL 2024 Remote- duty station Washington DC

CONSULTANT THE WORLD BANK

- Data curation and analysis
- Writing policy papers

10 AUG 2023 - 16 DEC 2023 Blantyre, Malawi

ECONOMICS LECTURER CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF MALAWI

- Teaching Agricultural Economics and Political Economy
- Conducting research
- Supervising students

JUL 2021 - DEC 2021 Remote- duty station Rome

CONSULTANT INTERNATIONAL FUND FOR AGRICULTURAL DEVELOPMENT

- Monitoring and evaluation

MAR 2020 - FEB 2021 Zomba, Malawi

RESEARCH ASSISTANT AGRICULTURAL POLICY RESEARCH IN AFRICA (APRA)- RESEARCH PROGRAM CONSORTIUM

- Data management and analysis

2016 - 2020 Zomba, Malawi

RESEARCH ASSISTANT WADONDA CONSULT LIMITED

- Supervising data management team
- Data management and analysis
- Field work: Data collection

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Zomba, Malawi

COLLABORATIVE MASTER OF ARTS IN ECONOMICS University of Malawi

Website https://www.unima.ac.mw/

Lilongwe, Malawi

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN AGRICULTURAL AND APPLIED ECONOMICS University of Malawi, Bunda college

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): CHICHEWA

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Data analysis - Stata | • Data collection using CSPRO, KOBO, SURVEY CTO and ODK

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

Gottingen German

Gottingen Food Systems Symposium

Presenting on two research papers titled: Smallholder Farming Commercialization and Food Security in Malawi: Do Land Rights and Intrahousehold Bargaining Power Matter? and Gender differences and the welfare effects of food crop commercialization in Malawi

JUN 2022 - JUN 2022 Lilongwe Malawi

Agricultural Nutrition Health (ANH)

Presented a paper titled: The effects of remittances on household food nutrition security in the context of multiple shocks in Malawi

Link https://www.anh-academy.org/sites/default/files/2023-06/David Zingwe.pdf

NETWORKS AND MEMBERSHIPS

London

Development Studies Association

Link https://www.devstud.org.uk/members/dsa/42349

PROJECTS

2016 - 2018

World Bank-Malawi Education Sector Improvement Project, National Baseline Survey

PUBLICATIONS

2023

• The effects of remittances on household food and nutrition security in the context of multiple shocks in Malawi

Link https://doi.org/10.1080/23311932.2023.2238440

• The effects of engendered intra-household power dynamics on Household Food Security and Nutrition (Journal of Gender Studies)

Link https://doi.org/10.1080/09589236.2021.1940110

2024

<u>Comparative Impacts of Input Subsidies, Irrigation Investments, and Social Cash Transfers on Food and Nutrition Security in Malawi</u>

Link https://documents.worldbank.org/en/publication/documents-reports/documentdetail/099336405202431646

2022

• Use of Climate-Smart Agriculture Practices and Smallholder Farmer Market Participation in Central Malawi

Link https://opendocs.ids.ac.uk/opendocs/handle/20.500.12413/17112